>> Hi, everyone.
My name is Katherine Papoulias
[assumed spelling].
I'm a second year student in the
graduate program for Museum Studies
at San Francisco State University.
My background is in biology
and environmental policy,
and my emphasis in the program is
on education and interpretation.
The Global Museum on the San Francisco
State University campus has allowed me
to explore pretty much every
aspect of caring for museum,
from collections care behind the scenes,
to education on the public floor,
to museum management and fundraising.
We've learned a lot so far with this degree.
Now, I'm hoping to use all of these
skills to help change the world.
And I know that sounds really
cheesy, but just hear me out.
Museums are magical places.
Museums are the reason why
I studied what I studied,
why I care about the natural
world, why I want to protect it.
And museums feature so many different
types of things, not just animals or plants
in the Natural History Museum, but
art, and sculpture, and history.
Museums provide portals to the past.
They help us envision our future and connect
with the present all around the globe.
Now, I have been really lucky this
summer to work with the Global Museum
on some of their educational content.
We have an exhibition at the Global
Museum called Climate Stories.
It details the impacts of climate change on
indigenous communities all around the world
and features many different
objects from different cultures.
Now, what I've done the summer is develop
some lessons that take all of those stories
and bring them a little bit
closer to home using abalone.
Abalone are type of snail.
They've got these incredible shells,
and the Climate Stories Exhibition
features different objects
from around the world with
different types of shells.
But I wanted to take all of the
stories, bring them here to Bay Area,
because abalone are incredibly
important here in California.
They were not only important for the fishing
industry over the last hundred years or so,
but they've been used for thousands of years by
indigenous communities he's here in California,
including the Ohlone here in the Bay Area.
Now, what I've done is create some lesson
plans that talk about abalone as an animal,
talk about abalone as place in
California history, and some of the ways
that we can protect abalone for the future.
Keep an eye on the Global Museum
website for these lessons.
They'll be coming pretty soon.
But in the meantime, I'll show you a quick
kind of craft project you can do at home.
One of the most well-known
features of an abalone is its shell.
Not necessarily the outside though.
The outside of an abalone shell
might be colorful, might be faded,
might be pitted from boring sponges,
it might be covered in algae,
and it might have some hitchhikers,
like barnacles or snails,
but the inside of their shell is rainbow.
They have this incredible iridescent
coloration coming from a structure called nacre,
which we can also call Mother of Pearl.
It makes the shell super
strong and it's really pretty.
Now, we see iridescence in a lot of other
things, in some rocks, for example, feathers,
inside of mussel shells, but not everyone
has all of this iridescent material at home.
So we're going to learn a little bit more about
abalone and their iridescence by making our own.
Now, to do this craft, you will
need a shallow dish of water,
some black paper, and some clear nail polish.
First step is to take your clear nail
polish and gently touch the surface
of the brush to the surface of the water.
Now, you'll see it kind of spread across.
Take your black strip of paper,
gently dunk it in your water
so that the nail polish wraps around the paper.
And then what you have, it's a
little hard to see on camera here,
but you end up with these beautiful
kind of rainbow shimmering strips.
You can kind of see in the light there.
When you let it dry, you can use it as a
bookmark or anything else you can think of.
If you want, you can even
make your own abalone with it.
We have a craft coming to the
Global Museum website soon
to make your own paper mache abalone.
You can see a decorated top of mine here with a
little bit of color, it's red abalone after all,
and some barnacles made out of clay,
some fake moss to act as algae.
And then the ,inside I've covered with
some iridescent paper that I made using
that exact technique I just showed you.
If you make iridescent paper at home or a
paper mache abalone, we'd love to see it.
Stay tuned and keep an eye on the Global
Museum website for more crafts and lessons
about abalone, and tag us on social
media if you make any of these crafts.
We would really love to see them.
Thank you so much for joining,
and happy crafting.